Inventory of the Willard L. Gorton papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Willard L. Gorton papers
1927-1932
XX167
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes (1.0 linear foot)
Correspondence, reports, clippings, and photographs, relating to reclamation and irrigation projects in Turkestan.
Gorton, Willard L., 1881-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Agriculture--Soviet Central Asia.; Engineers.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Central Asia.; Soviet Union--Economic policy--1928-1932.; Soviet Union.
- Agreement between the Soviet Union Mid-Asian Water Economy Service (SREDAZVODOZ) and W. L. Gorton on and an organizational chart, photostats and negative, 1930 February 6 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Correspondence and personal papers regarding W. L. Gorton's appointment as consulting engineer in irrigation service with the Mid-Asian Reclamation Service in Tashkent, Uzbek Republic (Turkestan), USSR, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Reclamation and Irrigation Engineering in Turkestan, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
- Food orders to America and related correspondence from Turkestan, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Reports, articles, notes, etc. on Soviet Russia, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Reports, articles, notes, etc. on Soviet Russia, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Clippings on Soviet Russia (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
- United States recognition of Soviet Russia (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Personal memorabilia of W. L. Gorton (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Photographs, undated
  - Places of religious worship and people, 57 prints and 3 negatives (Envelope A)
  - 95 prints and 25 negatives of the populace at work (Envelope B)
  - 65 prints and 14 negatives of street scenes, populace, and scenery (Envelope C)
  - Western USSR and Europe: 96 prints and 130 negatives (Envelope D)